## TAI (AIDEN) PHAM

Full Stack Developer specializing in Javascript/Typescript with more than 4 years experience. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for front-end and back-end projects. Operated in numerous Javascript frameworks, libraries and databases. Deployed projects on AWS. Coordinated a team of fresher and junior developers. Always ready for a new challenge.

# Technical Skills

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, React, React Native, Redux, Jquery, Websocket, Socketio, Emotion, Styledcomponent, Material-UI, Ant design, Tailwindcss, Openlayers.
- Backend: Express, Fastify, Sailjs, GraphQL, Serverless framework, mongooes, .
- Database: Postgres, MySQL, MariaDB, Mongodb, Redis.
- Search engine: Elasticsearch.
- Cloud service: Cloudfront, S3, EC2, RDS, Lambda, API gateway, Elasticsearch service, Mongo Atlas.
- **Container:** Docker. • Web Server : Nginx.

## Work Experience



## Full Stack Developer - VDC in partnership with PYCOGroup - 7/2020 to present

### Simple Home Loan

- Tech: React, Redux, Graphql, Nodejs, Typescript.
- **Description**: A miniapp for fullly processing home loan application from a customer, used by banker. Bankers will use this app to handle all customer's information such as consents, products, financials...; by that it can quickly help the bankers to make the decision to issue a home loan.
- Page: Internal tools for bankers at https://www.nab.com.au

## Full Stack Developer - Spiritlabs - 10/2018 to 7/2020

#### 1. SFF x Switch Go

- **Tech**: React, Redux, SocketIO, Fastify, MongoDB, Elasticsearch.
- Service: AWS EC2, AWS S3, Videospace, Gevme
- **Description**: Youtube-liked, video platform focusing in Fintech.
- Role: Team lead, working directly with BA and PM to plan tasks and features. Coordinated teamwork using agile approach. Initialized and contributed for both FE and BE. Supporting team member to overcome issues, planing task.
- Achievement: Became team lead (acting), gained experience on working with elasticsearch, won a valuable client for the company.
- Page: https://go.sffxswitch.com

#### 2. Hex Safe

- **Tech**: React, Redux, JQuery, Express, MariaDB.
- **Description**: Institutional custody for cryptocurrencies.
- **Role**: Frontend developer, working with designer and Back end team for smooth FE integration. Helped defining API. Prepare API for upcoming features.
- Achievement: Gained knowledge on cryptocurrency transaction.
- Page: Hexsafe

#### 3. Teemie

- Tech: React, Redux, React native, Sailjs, MongoDB.
- Service: AWS EC2, AWS S3, Visual Studio App Center.
- **Description**: Management tool built specifically for industries where managers and staff are on the go!.
- Role: Full stack developer, contributed to web app (manager), mobile app (staff) and server.
- Page: https://teemieapp.com

## 4. Fluentup

- Tech: React, Redux, Expressjs, MongoDB.
- Service: AWS EC2, AWS S3.
- **Description**: Online language learning platform.
- **Role**: Full stack developer.
- Page: https://fluentup.com

## Front End Developer - Saigon Technology Solutions - 10/2017 to 10/2018

#### 5. Riskview

- **Tech**: React Native, Redux saga.
- **Description**: Risk and assurance management app.
- Role: Front end developer, communicating with Australian team lead.
- **Achievement**: Promoted to Intermediate developer, gained experience in files uploading and downloading for both ios and android.
- Page: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/meercat-riskview/id1279108658

#### 6. Fiviva

- Tech: React Native, Redux.
- Service: Quickblox.
- **Description**: A sharing economy apps for selling and buying real estates.
- Role: Front end developer, implemented Quickblox messaging service.
- Achievement: Get experience in implementing messaging system using Quickblox.

#### 7. TeamAssurance

- Tech: React, Redux.
- **Description**: Team management web app.
- Role: Front end developer, communicating with Australian team lead.
- Page: https://www.teamassurance.com

## Software engineer - Robert Bosch Engineering and Business Solutions - 9/2016 to 10/2017

## 8. Toolshop

- **Tech**: React, Redux.
- **Description**: A guide web app for displaying seat, room and building locations around workplace.
- Role: Front end developer.
- Achievement: Gained experience in implementing live chart, optimized components.

## 9. Seat Tracking

- **Tech**: React, Redux.
- **Description**: To be used locally on factory side, for monitoring machines and managing tools.
- Role: Front end developer.
- Achievement: Gained experience in working with SVG.

#### 10. MineSmart

- Tech: React, Redux, Openlayers.
- Description: Using Openlayers to create a controllers panel then users can use these controllers to draw, edit features on a map.
- Role: Front end developer, received requirements directly from India team.
- **Achievement**: Gained experience in working with map-based library.

# Soft Skills



- Ability to manage multiple projects and consistently meet deadlines.
- Communicate and cooperate well with colleagues.
- Adaptable and willing to learn new technologies.
- Working proficiency in English.
- Excellent research, problems solving skills.
- Self taught.

## Education 7



- Bachelor of Computer Science Sep 2016 Ton Duc Thang University, Ho Chi Minh
- Scored **870 out of 990** on the Test of English for International Communication (TOEIC).

### Contact

- +84 909 840 720
- phamtai2119@gmail.com
- https://taipham.dev
- Github
- Linkedin